<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kym Derriman</title>
    <link>https://kymderriman.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kym Derriman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:09:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kymderriman.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Population Inversion, Lasers, Photons, Electrons and a Lame Party.</title>
      <link>https://kymderriman.com/posts/pop-inversion-lasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 11:09:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kymderriman.com/posts/pop-inversion-lasers/</guid>
      <description>Population inversion has been a tricky concept for me. How can a photon, crashing into an electron, something that usually adds energy, actually cause the electron to lose energy?&#xA;This isn’t meant to be a rigorous treatment of this topic, but rather a helpful way to think about this intuitively so that it doesn’t feel so wrong.&#xA;In short, I think of this phenomenon by personifying the objects in question.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Success! Automatic Scanning of Interference Patterns.</title>
      <link>https://kymderriman.com/posts/interference-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:37:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kymderriman.com/posts/interference-experiment/</guid>
      <description>Finally! I’ve been trying to get this experiment to work for a while but I the signal was always too weak. In class with Dr. Podzorov, we learned about op-amps so I figured I’d give it a shot to finally get this experiment working. It worked!&#xA;In David and Shanni Prutchi’s book Exploring Quantum Physics Through Hands-On Projects, one of the first experiments they describe is a way to automatically scan the interference pattern produced by something like a laser shining through a double-slit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog</title>
      <link>https://kymderriman.com/posts/hello-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:10:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kymderriman.com/posts/hello-blog/</guid>
      <description>For now this is intended to be my second brain. Bring together the scattered notes from notebooks, post-its, book margins, the cloud, local files, wherever. Also kind of an open journal. Things that, while they may be personal, like most things I don’t mind them being publicly visible.&#xA;So a little bit of a status brain dump to begin. We’ve got a few things going on actively or tumbling around the back of the brain.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
